Pradeep Mishra

Machine Learning Specialist at Kaybus

pradeepgmishra@gmail.com

Summary

I am a passionate Solution Developer with strong beliefs in Model Thinking, Recombination methods and Blue Ocean innovation strategies transcending traditional ways of developing solutions. I often use unconventional methods for deriving deep insights, understanding patterns, modelling processes and behaviors. Strong analytical skills and knowledge of statistical tools and techniques. Creative solutions, inspired by lateral thinking, not limited or inhibited by standard boundaries, will drive the future. I am also interested in biomimicry (biomimetics), (renewable) energy, semantic web and relevance. I have exp in unconventional internet-driven eCommerce & virtual assistant products, applied nlp, machine learning, clustering, personalization etc Other Interests: SEO, Website Perfomance Optimization, Algorithms, Wordpress, Competetive Strategies Clients I have worked with: Intuit, DHL, Telstra Corporation Ltd, Mitsubishi Fuso Truck and Bus Corporation, Procter & Gamble, Sify. Domains: ECommerce, Knowledge Engineering, News, Logistics, Transport, Telecommunication, Taxation, Accounting, Internet. Tools & Technologies: Java (SCJP certified), R, Ruby, Php, MySql, RDF, Apache Jena, Spring, Hibernate, SPARQL, SQL, Shell Website: www.praddy.in

Experience

Machine Learning Specialist at Kaybus

October 2013 - Present (1 year 7 months)

A game changer stealth startup

R&D Engineer (Technical Lead) at Glomantra eServices Pvt. Ltd.

September 2012 - September 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Developed a scalable Semantic Ontology Repository (SOR) for storing data about products (Retailer Catalog: Items, Brands, Manufacturers, Prices etc) in a linked manner in form of RDF and Triples. # Created a unique repository normalized using different aspects of retail industry and need understanding perspective # Created extensive indexing on SOR for very fast retrieval of semantically linked data using SOLR and Lucene. # Developed radical algorithms to understand user needs (search queries) using data in SOR # Developed algorithms for Main phrase detection from User queries and Item names # Developed algorithms for Detection of Attribute phrases from Item names using Grammar and pattern matching # Implemented Rule Engine driven complex retailer policies like 'Comparative price policy, Relevance (User profile and taste) policy, Loyalty Policy' etc # Did extensive data parsing and understanding based on large retailer catalogs

2 recommendations available upon request

Sr Software Engineer at Impetus

January 2012 - August 2012 (8 months)

Worked on QBO (Intuit) as consultant. Worked on DOJO - JS based framework Created txtweb based applications

RND Engineer at Glomantra eServices Pvt. Ltd.

December 2009 - January 2012 (2 years 2 months)

Developed modules for Mining, Processing and Processing of news articles. # Implemented algorithms for Document Clustering of news articles both in database and in memory. # Did extensive performance improvement. # Developed a Recommendation Engine for recommending news articles to users based on past history of users, preferred news sources and news categories and a module for finding similar news articles. # Developed extensive caching mechanism for caching various responses for giving recommendations. # R&D on Stanford Natural Language Parser, Mallet Classifier and Stanford Named Entity Recogniser for parsing and understanding search queries entered by users. # Developed modules for searching celebrity related gossip from various sites on internet, filtering, ranking and aggregating the gossip articles. # Developed mechanism to separate gossip from news by using data from social networks (Twitter etc). # Performed Database clustering and synchronization for mysql database

Sr Software Engineer at Infosys Technologies Ltd.

November 2006 - November 2009 (3 years 1 month)

- Developed frameworks for Struts, EJB based enterprise web applications for Logistics and Travel domain.
- Worked on Oracle 10g, Informix database. Requirement Analysis (RA), Development and Testing of Applications. Met deadlines in fast-paced environment and function under high-pressures with extremely short deadlines. Served the role of KM (Knowledge Management) prime.

Software Trainee college at CMC Ahmd, A Tata Enterprise

November 2005 - May 2006 (7 months)

Worked as software trainee for completing final year industrial training. Duties included development, testing, bug fixing.

Certifications

Model Thinking

Coursera September 2014 to December 2014

R Programming

Coursera March 2015

The Data Scientist's Toolbox

Coursera March 2015

Critical Thinking in Global Challenges

Coursera February 2015 **Getting and Cleaning Data**

Coursera March 2015

Exploratory Data Analysis

Coursera March 2015

Test Scores

SCJP

November 2009 Score:85%

Sun Certified Java Professional

Languages

Hindi

English

(Full professional proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

Java Enterprise Edition

Hibernate

XML

Maven

Servlets

Oracle

Java

Struts

EJB

REST

Web Applications

Requirements Analysis

Web Services

AJAX

Spring

JavaScript

Weblogic

SOAP

WebSphere Application Server

WSDL

JAX-WS

VSS

Testing

MySQL

Databases

Core Java

Machine Learning

 \mathbf{R}

Data Science

Statistical Data Analysis

Search
Predictive Ana
Object Modelling
Heuristics
E-commerce
SEO
PHP
Internet Strategy
Mobile Applications

Spring Framework

Education

Dharmsinh Desai Institute of Technology

BE (CS), Computer Science, 2002 - 2006

Indrayon

HSC, Science, 1996 - 2002

Pradeep Mishra

Machine Learning Specialist at Kaybus

pradeepgmishra@gmail.com



2 people have recommended Pradeep

"Pradeep is an exceptional talent and an asset to any team. He delivered several complex bits of work with relative ease. His ability to learn and ramp up quickly on new tools was very helpful. His interest in learning combined with this ability meant that he was constantly improving. I would love to work with him again any time."

— Ramesh Narayanan, Director of Engineering, Glomantra eServices Pvt. Ltd., managed Pradeep at Glomantra eServices Pvt. Ltd.

"Pradeep worked on building Relevance Recommendation Platform that I led at GloMantra. Among many projects, his outstanding contribution has been in designing and implementing semantic models on top of Apache Jena. He is a good Java developer and a pleasant person to work with."

— Khanderao Kand, CTO, GloMantra Inc, managed Pradeep at Glomantra eServices Pvt. Ltd.

Contact Pradeep on LinkedIn